Myth number 7: my dog fears me and he know who's boss.
You need fear in your dog so that he respects you.
Wrong.
You want to make sure that your dog does things because he feels good about doing it.
Wants to please you, not out of fear.
Out of fear you're going to have all kinds of behavioral problems later also.
Apart from him being fearful of you, right?
The other day for example there was a customer where the German Shepherd was just jumping all over her.
She had scratches from here to here.
She told me my dog responds me, she comes to me, but she respects my husband more.
Well, the dog has to listen to you too, I told her.
Husband comes in late, dog's all over the place.
She's like we have to do something about this dog.
He yells at the dog, "Go to the kitchen!"
Like a bullet. I ask him the question, "Does the dog come to you when you call him?" He told me, "Well, apart from all these other problems we're having with the dog, I need to my dog to come to me when I call him."
What happen there is he got his result lesson taught.
He got the dog to do exactly what he wanted him to do, but he taught him the wrong lesson.
The lesson he taught him is to be fearful of him.
When he gets into the kitchen now the dog's in a back room, because that's the lesson that he taught him.
His got to the kitchen training when down the drain.
There's a difference between respect, which he was not respecting him, that's what she thought, and fear.